<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Skytools on The Art of PostgreSQL</title>
    <link>https://tapoueh.org/tags/skytools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Skytools on The Art of PostgreSQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 10:24:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tapoueh.org/tags/skytools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking at the SFPUG</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/07/talking-at-the-sfpug/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 10:24:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/07/talking-at-the-sfpug/</guid>
      <description>Those days feel really lucky to me. I&amp;rsquo;m currently visiting friends and customers in San Francisco, and really enjoying my trip here! Of course Josh Berkus took the opportunity to organise a SFPUG meeting and I had the pleasure of being the speaker over there.
My talk was about the most recent version of Skytools and the opportunity to realise that we&amp;rsquo;re still missing a lot on documentation. One of the attendee did propose to help us on that front as he apparently really likes technical writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bulk Replication</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/03/bulk-replication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 14:54:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/03/bulk-replication/</guid>
      <description>In the previous article here we talked about how to properly update more than one row at a time, under the title Batch Update. We did consider performances, including network round trips, and did look at the behavior of our results when used concurrently.
A case where we want to apply the previous article approach is when replicating data with a trigger based solution, such as SkyTools and londiste. Well, maybe not in all cases, we need to have a amount of UPDATE trafic worthy of setting up the solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Upgrading PGQ</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/02/live-upgrading-pgq/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 15:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/02/live-upgrading-pgq/</guid>
      <description>Some skytools related new today, it&amp;rsquo;s been a while. For those who where at my FOSDEM&amp;rsquo;s talk about Implementing High Availability you might have heard that I really like working with PGQ. A new version has been released a while ago, and the most recent verion is now 3.1.3, as announced in the Skytools 3.1.3 email.
Upgrade time!
Skytools 3.1.3 enters debian First news is that Skytools 3.1.3 has been entering debian today (I hope that by the time you reach that URL, it&amp;rsquo;s been updated to show information according to the news here, but I might be early).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean PGQ Subconsumers</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2012/04/clean-pgq-subconsumers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 15:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2012/04/clean-pgq-subconsumers/</guid>
      <description>Now that you&amp;rsquo;re all using the wonders of Cooperative Consumers to help you efficiently and reliably implement your business constraints and offload them from the main user transactions, you&amp;rsquo;re reaching a point where you have to clean up your development environment (because that&amp;rsquo;s what happens to development environments, right?), and you want a way to start again from a clean empty place.
Here we go. It used to be much more simple than that, so if you&amp;rsquo;re still using PGQ from Skytools2, just jump to the next step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skytools3: walmgr</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/09/skytools3-walmgr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 17:21:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/09/skytools3-walmgr/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s begin the Skytools 3 documentation effort, which is long overdue. The code is waiting for you over at github, and is stable and working. Why is it still in release candidate status, I hear you asking? Well because it&amp;rsquo;s missing updated documentation.
WalMgr is the Skytools component that manages WAL shipping for you, and archiving too. It knows how to prepare your master and standby setup, how to take a base backup and push it to the standby&amp;rsquo;s system, how to archive (at the satndby) master&amp;rsquo;s WAL files as they are produced and have the standby restore from this archive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skytools, version 3</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/08/skytools-version-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 21:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/08/skytools-version-3/</guid>
      <description>You can find skytools3 in debian experimental already, it&amp;rsquo;s in release candidate status. What&amp;rsquo;s missing is the documentation, so here&amp;rsquo;s an idea: I&amp;rsquo;m going to make a blog post series about skytools next features, how to use them, what they are good for, etc. This first article of the series will just list what are those new features.
Here are the slides from the CHAR(11) talk I made last month, about that very subject:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skytools3 : les slides</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/07/skytools3-les-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 14:39:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/07/skytools3-les-slides/</guid>
      <description>La conférence CHAR(11) étant maintenant terminée, il est d&amp;rsquo;usage de publier les slides utilisés. J&amp;rsquo;ai présenté Skytools 3.0 dont la prochaine version sera publiée dès que j&amp;rsquo;aurais eu le temps de terminer de revoir (en fait principalement d&amp;rsquo;écrire) la documentation.
  Les slides de l&amp;rsquo;ensemble des présentations devraient être publiés en ligne à terme, mais cela ne va pas pouvoir être fait aussi rapidement que nous le voudrions tous. Alors voici un peu de lecture en attendant la suite !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skytools3 talk Slides</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/07/skytools3-talk-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 14:24:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/07/skytools3-talk-slides/</guid>
      <description>In case you&amp;rsquo;re wondering, here are the slides from the CHAR(11) talk I gave, about Skytools 3.0, soon to be released. That means as soon as I have enough time available to polish (or write) the documentation.
  The slides for all the talks should eventually make their way to a central place, but expect some noticable delay here. Sorry about that, and have a good reading meanwhile!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De retour de CHAR(11)</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/07/de-retour-de-char11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/07/de-retour-de-char11/</guid>
      <description>Quelle meilleure occupation dans le train du retour de CHAR(11) que de se faire reporteur pour l&amp;rsquo;occasion ? En réalité, dormir serait une idée tant les soirées se sont prolongées !
Nous avons eu le plaisir d&amp;rsquo;écouter Jan Wieck présenter un historique simplifié de la réplication avec PostgreSQL. Étant lui-même l&amp;rsquo;un des pionniers du domaine, son point de vue est des plus intéressants. Il a parlé de l&amp;rsquo;évolution des solutions de réplication, et je ne peux m&amp;rsquo;empêcher de penser que par bien des côtés Skytools est une évolution de Slony — Jan, auteur de Slony, semblait d&amp;rsquo;accord avec cela.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back From CHAR(11)</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/07/back-from-char11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 17:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/07/back-from-char11/</guid>
      <description>CHAR(11) finished somewhen in the night leading to today, if you consider the social events to be part of it, which I definitely do. This conference has been a very good one, both on the organisation side of things and of course for its content.
It began with a perspective about the evolution of replication solutions, by Jan Wieck himself. In some way Skytools is an evolution of Slony, in the sense that it reuses the same concepts, a part of the design, and even share bits of the implementation (like the txid_snapshot datatype that were added in PostgreSQL 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prêt pour CHAR(11) ?</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/07/pr%C3%AAt-pour-char11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 20:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/07/pr%C3%AAt-pour-char11/</guid>
      <description>La semaine prochaine déjà se tient CHAR(11), la conférence spécialisée sur le Clustering, la Haute Disponibilité et la Réplication avec PostgreSQL. C&amp;rsquo;est en Europe, à Cambridge cette fois, et c&amp;rsquo;est en anglais même si plusieurs compatriotes seront dans l&amp;rsquo;assistance.
Si vous n&amp;rsquo;avez pas encore jeté un œil au programme, je vous encourage à le faire. Même si vous n&amp;rsquo;aviez pas prévu de venir… parce qu&amp;rsquo;il y a de quoi vous faire changer d&amp;rsquo;avis !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back from Ottawa, preparing for Cambridge</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/05/back-from-ottawa-preparing-for-cambridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/05/back-from-ottawa-preparing-for-cambridge/</guid>
      <description>While Magnus is all about PG Conf EU already, you have to realize we&amp;rsquo;re just landed back from PG Con in Ottawa. My next stop in the annual conferences is CHAR 11, the Clustering, High Availability and Replication conference in Cambridge, 11-12 July. Yes, on the old continent this time.
This year&amp;rsquo;s pgcon hot topics, for me, have been centered around a better grasp at SSI and DDL Triggers. Having those beasts in PostgreSQL would allow for auditing, finer privileges management and some more automated replication facilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some notes about Skytools3</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/04/some-notes-about-skytools3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 11:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/04/some-notes-about-skytools3/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on skytools3 packaging lately. I&amp;rsquo;ve been pushing quite a lot of work into it, in order to have exactly what I needed out of the box, after some 3 years of production and experiences with the products. Plural, yes, because even if pgbouncer and plproxy are siblings to the projets (same developers team, separate life cycle and releases), then skytools still includes several sub-projects.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what the skytools3 packaging is going to look like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>towards pg_staging 1.0</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/03/towards-pg_staging-1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 15:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/03/towards-pg_staging-1.0/</guid>
      <description>If you don&amp;rsquo;t remember about what pg_staging is all about, it&amp;rsquo;s a central console from where to control all your PostgreSQL databases. Typically you use it to manage your development and pre-production setup, where developers ask you pretty often to install them some newer dump from the production, and you want that operation streamlined and easy.
Usage The typical session would be something like this:
pg_staging&amp;gt; databases foodb.dev foodb foodb_20100824 :5432 foodb_20100209 foodb_20100209 :5432 foodb_20100824 foodb_20100824 :5432 pgbouncer pgbouncer :6432 postgres postgres :5432 pg_staging&amp;gt; dbsizes foodb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pg_basebackup</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/11/pg_basebackup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 13:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/11/pg_basebackup/</guid>
      <description>Hannu just gave me a good idea in this email on -hackers, proposing that pg_basebackup should get the xlog files again and again in a loop for the whole duration of the base backup. That&amp;rsquo;s now done in the aforementioned tool, whose options got a little more useful now:
Usage: pg_basebackup.py [-v] [-f] [-j jobs] &amp;quot;dsn&amp;quot; dest Options: -h, --help show this help message and exit --version show version and quit -x, --pg_xlog backup the pg_xlog files -v, --verbose be verbose and about processing progress -d, --debug show debug information, including SQL queries -f, --force remove destination directory if it exists -j JOBS, --jobs=JOBS how many helper jobs to launch -D DELAY, --delay=DELAY pg_xlog subprocess loop delay, see -x -S, --slave auxilliary process --stdin get list of files to backup from stdin  Yeah, as implementing the xlog idea required having some kind of parallelism, I built on it and the script now has a --jobs option for you to setup how many processes to launch in parallel, all fetching some base backup files in its own standard ( libpq) PostgreSQL connection, in compressed chunks of 8 MB (so that&amp;rsquo;s not 8 MB chunks sent over).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PgCon 2009</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/05/pgcon-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/05/pgcon-2009/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t really compare PgCon 2009 with previous years versions, last time I enjoyed the event it was in 2006, in Toronto. But still I found the experience to be a great one, and I hope I&amp;rsquo;ll be there next year too!
I&amp;rsquo;ve met a lot of known people in the community, some of them I already had the chance to run into at Toronto or Prato, but this was the first time I got to talk to many of them about interresting projects and ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skytools 3.0 reaches alpha1</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/04/skytools-3.0-reaches-alpha1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/04/skytools-3.0-reaches-alpha1/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time for Skytools news again! First, we did improve documentation of current stable branch with hosting high level presentations and tutorials on the PostgreSQL wiki. Do check out the Londiste Tutorial, it seems that&amp;rsquo;s what people hesitating to try out londiste were missing the most.
The other things people miss out a lot in current stable Skytools (version 2.1.9 currently) are cascading replication (which allows for switchover and failover) and DDL support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asko Oja talks about Skype architecture</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/02/asko-oja-talks-about-skype-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/02/asko-oja-talks-about-skype-architecture/</guid>
      <description>In this russian page you&amp;rsquo;ll see a nice presentation of Skype databases architectures by Asko Oja himself. It&amp;rsquo;s the talk at Russian PostgreSQL Community meeting, October 2008, Moscow, and it&amp;rsquo;s a good read.
   
The presentation page is in russian but the slides are in English, so have a nice read!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skytools ticker daemon and londiste</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/02/skytools-ticker-daemon-and-londiste/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/02/skytools-ticker-daemon-and-londiste/</guid>
      <description>One of the difficulties in getting to understand and configure londiste reside in the relation between the ticker and the replication. This question was raised once more on IRC yesterday, so I made a new FAQ entry about it: How do this ticker thing relates to londiste?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Londiste and Slony</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/01/comparing-londiste-and-slony/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/01/comparing-londiste-and-slony/</guid>
      <description>In the page about Skytools I&amp;rsquo;ve encouraged people to ask some more questions in order for me to be able to try and answer them. That just happened, as usual on the #postgresql IRC, and the question is What does londiste lack that slony has?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Londiste Trick</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/01/londiste-trick/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/01/londiste-trick/</guid>
      <description>So, you&amp;rsquo;re using londiste and the ticker has not been running all night long, due to some restart glitch in your procedures, and the on call admin didn&amp;rsquo;t notice the restart failure. If you blindly restart the replication daemon, it will load in memory all those events produced during the night, at once, because you now have only one tick where to put them all.
The following query allows you to count how many events that represents, with the magic tick numbers coming from pgq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new site, using new software</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2008/12/new-site-using-new-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2008/12/new-site-using-new-software/</guid>
      <description>Oh and check out the skytools page too. Emacs Muse is so great a project that instead of just working on how to publish a website with this tool, I found myself editing a rather large document about londite.py.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>