<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mailq on The Art of PostgreSQL</title>
    <link>https://tapoueh.org/tags/mailq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mailq on The Art of PostgreSQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2011 14:10:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tapoueh.org/tags/mailq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mailq modeline display</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/05/mailq-modeline-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2011 14:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/05/mailq-modeline-display/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve not been following along, you might have missed it: it appears to me that even today, in 2011, mail systems work much better when setup the old way. Meaning with a local MTA for outgoing mail. With some niceties, such as sender dependent relayhost maps.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I needed M-x mailq to display the mail queue and have some easy shortcuts in order to operate it (mainly f runs the command mailq-mode-flush, but per site and per id delivery are useful too).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>el-get reaches 1.0</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/10/el-get-reaches-1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 13:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/10/el-get-reaches-1.0/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a week since the last commits in the el-get repository, and those were all about fixing and adding recipes, and about notifications. Nothing like core plumbing you see. Also, 0.9 was released on 2010-08-24 and felt pretty complete already, then received lots of improvements. It&amp;rsquo;s high time to cross the line and call it 1.0!
Now existing users will certainly just be moderatly happy to see the tool reach that version number, depending whether they think more about the bugs they want to see fixed (ftp is supported, only called http) and the new features they want to see in ( info documentation) or more about what el-get does for them already today&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postfix sender_dependent_relayhost_maps</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/09/postfix-sender_dependent_relayhost_maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/09/postfix-sender_dependent_relayhost_maps/</guid>
      <description>The previous article about M-x mailq has raised several mails asking me details about the Postfix setup I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. The problem we&amp;rsquo;re trying to solve is having a local MTA to send mails, so that any old-style Unix tool just works, instead of only the MUA you&amp;rsquo;ve spent time setting up.
Postfix makes it possible to do that quite easily, but it gets a little more involved if you have more than one relayhost that you want to use depending on your current From address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scratch that itch: M-x mailq</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/09/scratch-that-itch-m-x-mailq/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/09/scratch-that-itch-m-x-mailq/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, most people would think that email is something simple, you just setup your preferred client (that&amp;rsquo;s called a MUA) with some information such as the smtp host you want it to talk to (that&amp;rsquo;s call a MTA and this one is your relayhost). Then there&amp;rsquo;s all the receiving mails part, and that&amp;rsquo;s smtp again on the server side. Then there&amp;rsquo;s how to get those mail, read them, flag them, manage them, and that&amp;rsquo;s better served by IMAP.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>