<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book on The Art of PostgreSQL</title>
    <link>https://tapoueh.org/categories/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book on The Art of PostgreSQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 09:34:36 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tapoueh.org/categories/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s in a name: “Mastering”</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2017/11/whats-in-a-name-mastering/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 09:34:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2017/11/whats-in-a-name-mastering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that my book &lt;a href=&#34;https://masteringpostgresql.com&#34;&gt;Mastering PostgreSQL in Application
Development&lt;/a&gt; is released (and selling well,
thanks guys!), I&amp;rsquo;ve had some questions about the title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is that to become good at anything, we need to practice. We
practice a lot, and it&amp;rsquo;s even better when we are actively trying to learn,
following what&amp;rsquo;s named &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Practice_(learning_method)#Deliberate_practice&#34;&gt;deliberate
practice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering PostgreSQL in Application Development launches!</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2017/11/mastering-postgresql-in-application-development-launches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 10:48:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2017/11/mastering-postgresql-in-application-development-launches/</guid>
      <description>Today is the day my book Mastering PostgreSQL in Application Development launches! I&amp;rsquo;m all excited that everybody interested is now able to actually read my book!
Mastering PostgreSQL in Application Development targets application developers who want to learn SQL properly, and actually master this programming language. Most developers don&amp;rsquo;t think of SQL as a programming language, mainly because they don&amp;rsquo;t have full control of the execution plan of their queries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering PostgreSQL in Application Development</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2017/09/mastering-postgresql-in-application-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 15:22:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2017/09/mastering-postgresql-in-application-development/</guid>
      <description>Mastering PostgreSQL in Application Development is the full title of the book I am currently writing. Running the PostgreSQL is YeSQL series of blog posts has shown me developers need a PostgreSQL book for developers. A book with the same properties as the YeSQL series articles in this blog:
 we use real world data sets to put every query and SQL technique we learn in the context of a user story or business case,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering PostgreSQL in Application Development</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 01:16:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/book/</guid>
      <description>I am writing a book to share my knowledge about how to best use PostgreSQL as an application developer. If you&amp;rsquo;ve evered ask yourself how much should I have my database do for me? this book is for you. If you&amp;rsquo;re thinking that using an ORM might not always be the best option out there, if sometimes you wish SQL was easier to maintain than those concatenated strings with conditionals, then this book can&amp;rsquo;t wait for you!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
