<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Muse on Dimitri Fontaine, PostgreSQL Expert</title>
    <link>http://tapoueh.org/tags/muse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Muse on Dimitri Fontaine, PostgreSQL Expert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 13:34:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tapoueh.org/tags/muse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Muse meets Common Lisp</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/07/emacs-muse-meets-common-lisp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 13:34:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/07/emacs-muse-meets-common-lisp/</guid>
      <description>This blog of mine is written in the very good Emacs Muse format, that I find much more friendly to writing articles than both org-mode and markdown-mode that I both use in a regular basis too. The main think that I like in Muse that those two others lack is the support for displaying images inline.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what it looks like to edit with Emacs Muse
The Muse publishing system The idea is that you edit .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elisp Breadcrumbs</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/07/elisp-breadcrumbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 18:44:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/07/elisp-breadcrumbs/</guid>
      <description>A breadcrumb is a navigation aid. I just added one to this website, so that it gets easier to browse from any article to its local and parents indexes and back to /dev/dim, the root webpage of this site.
As it was not that much work to implement, here&amp;rsquo;s the whole of it:
;;; ;;; Breadcrumb support ;;; (defun tapoueh-breadcrumb-to-current-page () &amp;quot;Return a list of (name . link) from the index root page to current one&amp;quot; (let* ((current (muse-current-file)) (cwd (file-name-directory current)) (project (muse-project-of-file current)) (root (muse-style-element :path (caddr project))) (path (tapoueh-path-to-root)) (dirs (split-string (file-relative-name current root) &amp;quot;/&amp;quot;))) ;; (&amp;quot;blog&amp;quot; &amp;quot;2011&amp;quot; &amp;quot;07&amp;quot; &amp;quot;13-back-from-char11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muse setup revised</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/07/muse-setup-revised/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 19:55:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/07/muse-setup-revised/</guid>
      <description>Most of you are probably reading my posts directly in their RSS reader tools (mine is gnus thanks to the Gwene service), so you probably missed it, but I just pushed a whole new version of my website, still using Emacs Muse as the engine.
My setup is tentatively called tapoueh.el and browsable online. It consists of some tweaks on top of Muse, so that I can enjoy tags and proper rss support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>el-get reaches 1.0</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/10/el-get-reaches-1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 13:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/10/el-get-reaches-1.0/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a week since the last commits in the el-get repository, and those were all about fixing and adding recipes, and about notifications. Nothing like core plumbing you see. Also, 0.9 was released on 2010-08-24 and felt pretty complete already, then received lots of improvements. It&amp;rsquo;s high time to cross the line and call it 1.0!
Now existing users will certainly just be moderatly happy to see the tool reach that version number, depending whether they think more about the bugs they want to see fixed (ftp is supported, only called http) and the new features they want to see in ( info documentation) or more about what el-get does for them already today&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want to share your recipes?</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/08/want-to-share-your-recipes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 14:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/08/want-to-share-your-recipes/</guid>
      <description>Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s another el-get related entry. It seems to take a lot of my attention these days. After having setup the git repository so that you can update el-get from within itself (so that it&amp;rsquo;s self-contained), the next logical step is providing recipes.
By that I mean that el-get-sources entries will certainly look a lot alike between a user and another. Let&amp;rsquo;s take the el-get entry itself:
(:name el-get :type git :url &amp;quot;git://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>el-get</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/08/el-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 22:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/08/el-get/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using emacs for a long time, and a long time it took me to consider learning Emacs Lisp. Before that, I didn&amp;rsquo;t trust my level of understanding enough to be comfortable in managing my setup efficiently.
One of the main problems of setting up Emacs is that not only you tend to accumulate so many tricks from EmacsWiki and blog posts that your .emacs has to grow to a full ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Muse hacking</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/03/emacs-muse-hacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 13:33:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/03/emacs-muse-hacking/</guid>
      <description>Now you know what piece of software is used to publish this blog. I really like it, the major mode makes it a great experience to be using this tool, and the fact that you produce the HTML and rsync it all from within Emacs ( C-c C-p then C-c C-r with some easy elisp code) is a big advantage as far as I&amp;rsquo;m concerned. No need to resort to shell and Makefile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Muse based publishing</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/10/emacs-muse-based-publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 17:23:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/10/emacs-muse-based-publishing/</guid>
      <description>As you might have noticed, this little blog of mine is not compromising much and entirely maintained from Emacs. Until today, I had to resort to term to upload my publications, though, as I&amp;rsquo;ve been too lazy to hack up the tools integration for simply doing a single rsync command line. That was one time to many:
(defvar dim:muse-rsync-options &amp;quot;-avz&amp;quot; &amp;quot;rsync options&amp;quot;) (defvar dim:muse-rsync-source &amp;quot;~/dev/muse/out&amp;quot; &amp;quot;local path from where to rsync, with no ending /&amp;quot;) (defvar dim:muse-rsync-target &amp;quot;dim@tapoueh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emacs-snapshot</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2008/12/emacs-snapshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2008 16:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2008/12/emacs-snapshot/</guid>
      <description>If you want to live on the bleeding edge, it&amp;rsquo;s easy enough to get a non existing release of GNU Emacs under debian sid, thanks to http://emacs.orebokech.com/.
The problem is that Emacs Muse is broken on emacs-snapshot, partly because of Htmlize which is unable to find the face fonts (I got (error &amp;quot;Invalid face&amp;quot;)), partly because of my configuration itself:
hunk ./dim-muse.el 22 - &#39;((&amp;quot;pgsql.tapoueh.org&amp;quot; $ - (,@(muse-project-alist-dirs &amp;quot;~/dev/muse/site&amp;quot;) $ + &#39;((&amp;quot;pgsql.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new site, using new software</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2008/12/new-site-using-new-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2008/12/new-site-using-new-software/</guid>
      <description>Oh and check out the skytools page too. Emacs Muse is so great a project that instead of just working on how to publish a website with this tool, I found myself editing a rather large document about londite.py.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Muse powered blog</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2008/12/emacs-muse-powered-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2008/12/emacs-muse-powered-blog/</guid>
      <description>So finaly a blogging software for geeks exists?
 The problem with communication is that you think it happened.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fake entry</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2008/12/fake-entry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2008/12/fake-entry/</guid>
      <description>This is a test of a fake entry to see how muse will manage this.
With some SQL inside:
 SELECT * FROM planet.postgresql.org WHERE author = &amp;quot;dim&amp;quot;; 
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>