<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Extensions on The Art of PostgreSQL</title>
    <link>https://tapoueh.org/categories/extensions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Extensions on The Art of PostgreSQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 17:53:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tapoueh.org/categories/extensions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Extensions Templates</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/01/extensions-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 17:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/01/extensions-templates/</guid>
      <description>In a recent article titled Inline Extensions we detailed the problem of how to distribute an extension&amp;rsquo;s package to a remote server without having access to its file system at all. The solution to that problem is non trivial, let&amp;rsquo;s say. But thanks to the awesome PostgreSQL Community we finaly have some practical ideas on how to address the problem as discussed on pgsql-hackers, our development mailing list.
PostgreSQL is first an Awesome Community</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inline Extensions</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2012/12/inline-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 11:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2012/12/inline-extensions/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been having the CREATE EXTENSION feature in PostgreSQL for a couple of releases now, so let&amp;rsquo;s talk about how to go from here. The first goal of the extension facility has been to allow for a clean dump and restore process of contrib modules. As such it&amp;rsquo;s been tailored to the needs of deploying files on the file system because there&amp;rsquo;s no escaping from that when you have to ship binary and executable files, those infamous .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extension White Listing</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2012/03/extension-white-listing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2012 14:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2012/03/extension-white-listing/</guid>
      <description>PostgreSQL 9.1 includes proper extension support, as you might well know if you ever read this very blog here. Some hosting facilities are playing with PostgreSQL at big scale (hello Heroku!) and still meet with small caveats making their life uneasy.
To be specific, only superusers are allowed to install C coded stored procedures, and that impacts a lot of very useful PostgreSQL extension: all those shiped in the contrib package are coded in C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Stored Procedures</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/10/scaling-stored-procedures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 18:23:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/10/scaling-stored-procedures/</guid>
      <description>In the news recently stored procedures where used as an excuse for moving away logic from the database layer to application layer, and to migrate away from a powerful technology to a simpler one, now that there&amp;rsquo;s no logic anymore in the database.
It&amp;rsquo;s not the way I would typically approach scaling problems, and apparently I&amp;rsquo;m not alone on the Stored Procedures camp. Did you read this nice blog post Mythbusters: Stored Procedures Edition already?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for PGCON</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/05/preparing-for-pgcon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/05/preparing-for-pgcon/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s this time of the year again, the main international PostgreSQL Conference is next week in Ottawa, Canada. If previous years are any indication, this will be great event where to meet with a lot of the members of your community. The core team will be there, developers will be there, and we will meet with users and their challenging use cases.
This is a very good time to review both what you did in the project those last 12 months, and what you plan to do next year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extensions: writing a patch for PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/10/extensions-writing-a-patch-for-postgresql/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 11:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/10/extensions-writing-a-patch-for-postgresql/</guid>
      <description>These days, thanks to my community oriented job, I&amp;rsquo;m working full time on a PostgreSQL patch to terminate basic support for extending SQL. First thing I want to share is that patching the backend code is not as hard as one would think. Second one is that git really is helping.
“Not as hard as one would think, are you kidding me?”, I hear some say. Well, that&amp;rsquo;s true. It&amp;rsquo;s C code in there, but with a very good layer of abstractions so that you&amp;rsquo;re not dealing with subtle problems that much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resuming work on Extensions, first little step</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/10/resuming-work-on-extensions-first-little-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 17:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/10/resuming-work-on-extensions-first-little-step/</guid>
      <description>Yeah I&amp;rsquo;m back on working on my part of the extension thing in PostgreSQL.
First step is a little one, but as it has public consequences, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d talk about it already. I&amp;rsquo;ve just refreshed my git repository to follow the new master one, and you can see that here http://git.postgresql.org/gitweb?p=postgresql-extension.git;a=commitdiff;h=9a88e9de246218e93c04b6b97e1ef61d97925430.
It&amp;rsquo;s been easier than I feared, mainly:
$ git --no-pager diff master..extension $ git --no-pager format-patch master..extension $ cp 0001-First-stab-at-writing-pg_execute_from_file-function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back from PgCon2010</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/05/back-from-pgcon2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 14:26:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/05/back-from-pgcon2010/</guid>
      <description>This year&amp;rsquo;s edition has been the best pgcon ever for me. Granted, it&amp;rsquo;s only my third time, but still :) As Josh said the &amp;ldquo;Hall Track&amp;rdquo; in particular was very good, and the Dev Meeting has been very effective!
Extensions This time I prepared some slides to present the extension design and I tried hard to make it so that we get to agree on a plan, even recognizing it&amp;rsquo;s not solving all of our problems from the get go.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>