<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pgcon on The Art of PostgreSQL</title>
    <link>https://tapoueh.org/tags/pgcon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pgcon on The Art of PostgreSQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 11:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tapoueh.org/tags/pgcon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Back from Ottawa, preparing for Cambridge</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/05/back-from-ottawa-preparing-for-cambridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/05/back-from-ottawa-preparing-for-cambridge/</guid>
      <description>While Magnus is all about PG Conf EU already, you have to realize we&amp;rsquo;re just landed back from PG Con in Ottawa. My next stop in the annual conferences is CHAR 11, the Clustering, High Availability and Replication conference in Cambridge, 11-12 July. Yes, on the old continent this time.
This year&amp;rsquo;s pgcon hot topics, for me, have been centered around a better grasp at SSI and DDL Triggers. Having those beasts in PostgreSQL would allow for auditing, finer privileges management and some more automated replication facilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for PGCON</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/05/preparing-for-pgcon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/05/preparing-for-pgcon/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s this time of the year again, the main international PostgreSQL Conference is next week in Ottawa, Canada. If previous years are any indication, this will be great event where to meet with a lot of the members of your community. The core team will be there, developers will be there, and we will meet with users and their challenging use cases.
This is a very good time to review both what you did in the project those last 12 months, and what you plan to do next year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extensions in 9.1</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/03/extensions-in-9.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 16:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/03/extensions-in-9.1/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve not been following closely you might have missed out on extensions integration. Well, Tom spent some time on the patches I&amp;rsquo;ve been preparing for the last 4 months. And not only did he commit most of the work but he also enhanced some parts of the code (better factoring) and basically finished it.
At the previous developer meeting his advice was to avoid putting too much into the very first version of the patch for it to stand its chances of being integrated, and while in the review process more than one major PostgreSQL contributor expressed worries about the size of the patch and the number of features proposed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back from CHAR(10)</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/07/back-from-char10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/07/back-from-char10/</guid>
      <description>It surely does not feel like a full month and some more went by since we were enjoying PGCon 2010, but in fact it was already the time for CHAR(10). The venue was most excellent, as Oxford is a very beautiful city. Also, the college was like a city in the city, and having the accomodation all in there really smoothed it all.
On a more technical viewpoint, the range of topics we talked about and the even broader one in the &amp;ldquo;Hall Track&amp;rdquo; make my mind full of ideas, again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back from PgCon2010</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/05/back-from-pgcon2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 14:26:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/05/back-from-pgcon2010/</guid>
      <description>This year&amp;rsquo;s edition has been the best pgcon ever for me. Granted, it&amp;rsquo;s only my third time, but still :) As Josh said the &amp;ldquo;Hall Track&amp;rdquo; in particular was very good, and the Dev Meeting has been very effective!
Extensions This time I prepared some slides to present the extension design and I tried hard to make it so that we get to agree on a plan, even recognizing it&amp;rsquo;s not solving all of our problems from the get go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PgCon 2009</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/05/pgcon-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/05/pgcon-2009/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t really compare PgCon 2009 with previous years versions, last time I enjoyed the event it was in 2006, in Toronto. But still I found the experience to be a great one, and I hope I&amp;rsquo;ll be there next year too!
I&amp;rsquo;ve met a lot of known people in the community, some of them I already had the chance to run into at Toronto or Prato, but this was the first time I got to talk to many of them about interresting projects and ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
