<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Debian on Dimitri Fontaine, Expert PostgreSQL</title>
    <link>http://tapoueh.org/tags/debian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Debian on Dimitri Fontaine, Expert PostgreSQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 16:06:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tapoueh.org/tags/debian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quicklisp and debian</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2015/05/quicklisp-and-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 16:06:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2015/05/quicklisp-and-debian/</guid>
      <description>Common Lisp users are very happy to use Quicklisp when it comes to downloading and maintaining dependencies between their own code and the librairies it is using.
Sometimes I am pointed that when compared to other programming languages Common Lisp is lacking a lot in the batteries included area. After having had to package about 50 common lisp librairies for debian I can tell you that I politely disagree with that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Upgrading PGQ</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/02/live-upgrading-pgq/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 15:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/02/live-upgrading-pgq/</guid>
      <description>Some skytools related new today, it&amp;rsquo;s been a while. For those who where at my FOSDEM&amp;rsquo;s talk about Implementing High Availability you might have heard that I really like working with PGQ. A new version has been released a while ago, and the most recent verion is now 3.1.3, as announced in the Skytools 3.1.3 email.
Upgrade time!
Skytools 3.1.3 enters debian First news is that Skytools 3.1.3 has been entering debian today (I hope that by the time you reach that URL, it&amp;rsquo;s been updated to show information according to the news here, but I might be early).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL and debian</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/09/postgresql-and-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 17:14:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/09/postgresql-and-debian/</guid>
      <description>After talking about it for a very long time, work finally did begin! I&amp;rsquo;m talking about the apt.postgresql.org build system that will allow us, in the long run, to propose debian versions of binary packages for PostgreSQL and its extensions, compiled for a bunch of debian and ubuntu versions.
We&amp;rsquo;re now thinking to support the i386 and amd64 architectures for lenny, squeeze, wheezy and sid, and also for maverick and natty, maybe oneiric too while at it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pgfincore in debian</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/08/pgfincore-in-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2011 23:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/08/pgfincore-in-debian/</guid>
      <description>As of pretty recently, pgfincore is now in debian, as you can see on its postgresql-9.0-pgfincore page. The reason why it entered the debian archives is that it reached the 1.0 release!
Rather than talking about what pgfincore is all about ( A set of functions to manage pages in memory from PostgreSQL), I will talk about its packaging and support as a debian package. Here&amp;rsquo;s the first example of a modern multi-version packaging I have to offer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Version support for Extensions</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/06/multi-version-support-for-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 09:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/06/multi-version-support-for-extensions/</guid>
      <description>We still have this problem to solve with extensions and their packaging. How to best organize things so that your extension is compatible with before 9.1 and 9.1 and following releases of PostgreSQL?
Well, I had to do it for the ip4r contribution, and I wanted the following to happen:
dpkg-deb: building package `postgresql-8.3-ip4r&#39; ... dpkg-deb: building package `postgresql-8.4-ip4r&#39; ... dpkg-deb: building package `postgresql-9.0-ip4r&#39; ... dpkg-deb: building package `postgresql-9.1-ip4r&#39; ...  And here&amp;rsquo;s a simple enough way to achieve that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back from Ottawa, preparing for Cambridge</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/05/back-from-ottawa-preparing-for-cambridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/05/back-from-ottawa-preparing-for-cambridge/</guid>
      <description>While Magnus is all about PG Conf EU already, you have to realize we&amp;rsquo;re just landed back from PG Con in Ottawa. My next stop in the annual conferences is CHAR 11, the Clustering, High Availability and Replication conference in Cambridge, 11-12 July. Yes, on the old continent this time.
This year&amp;rsquo;s pgcon hot topics, for me, have been centered around a better grasp at SSI and DDL Triggers. Having those beasts in PostgreSQL would allow for auditing, finer privileges management and some more automated replication facilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extension module_pathname and .sql.in</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/05/extension-module_pathname-and-.sql.in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/05/extension-module_pathname-and-.sql.in/</guid>
      <description>While currently too busy at work to deliver much Open Source contributions, let&amp;rsquo;s debunk an old habit of PostgreSQL extension authors. It&amp;rsquo;s all down to copy pasting from contrib, and there&amp;rsquo;s no reason to continue doing $libdir this way ever since 7.4 days.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example here, with the prefix extension. This one too will need some love, but is still behind on my spare time todo list, sorry about that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Kicker</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/04/emacs-kicker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 21:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/04/emacs-kicker/</guid>
      <description>Following up on the very popular emacs-starter-kit, I&amp;rsquo;m now proposing the emacs-kicker. It&amp;rsquo;s about the .emacs file you&amp;rsquo;ve seen in older posts here, which I maintain for some colleagues. After all, if they find it useful, some more people might to, so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to publish it.
What you&amp;rsquo;ll find is a very simple 128 lines Emacs user init file, based on el-get for external packages. A not so random selection of those is used, here&amp;rsquo;s the list when you hide some details:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some notes about Skytools3</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/04/some-notes-about-skytools3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 11:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/04/some-notes-about-skytools3/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on skytools3 packaging lately. I&amp;rsquo;ve been pushing quite a lot of work into it, in order to have exactly what I needed out of the box, after some 3 years of production and experiences with the products. Plural, yes, because even if pgbouncer and plproxy are siblings to the projets (same developers team, separate life cycle and releases), then skytools still includes several sub-projects.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what the skytools3 packaging is going to look like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extensions in 9.1</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/03/extensions-in-9.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 16:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/03/extensions-in-9.1/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve not been following closely you might have missed out on extensions integration. Well, Tom spent some time on the patches I&amp;rsquo;ve been preparing for the last 4 months. And not only did he commit most of the work but he also enhanced some parts of the code (better factoring) and basically finished it.
At the previous developer meeting his advice was to avoid putting too much into the very first version of the patch for it to stand its chances of being integrated, and while in the review process more than one major PostgreSQL contributor expressed worries about the size of the patch and the number of features proposed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>el-get 1.1, with 174 recipes</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/12/el-get-1.1-with-174-recipes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 16:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/12/el-get-1.1-with-174-recipes/</guid>
      <description>Yes, you read it well, el-get currently features 174 recipes, and is now reaching the 1.1 release. The reason for this release is mainly that I have two big chunks of code to review and the current code has been very stable for awhile. It seems better to do a release with the stable code that exists now before to shake it this much. If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering when to jump in the water and switch to using el-get, now is a pretty good time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>debian packaging PostgreSQL extensions</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/08/debian-packaging-postgresql-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/08/debian-packaging-postgresql-extensions/</guid>
      <description>In trying to help an extension debian packaging effort, I&amp;rsquo;ve once again proposed to handle it. That&amp;rsquo;s because I now begin to know how to do it, as you can see in my package overview page at debian QA facility. There&amp;rsquo;s a reason why I proposed myself here, it&amp;rsquo;s that yet another tool of mine is now to be found in debian, and should greatly help extension packaging there. You can already check for the postgresql-server-dev-all package page if you&amp;rsquo;re that impatient!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>el-get</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/08/el-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 22:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/08/el-get/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using emacs for a long time, and a long time it took me to consider learning Emacs Lisp. Before that, I didn&amp;rsquo;t trust my level of understanding enough to be comfortable in managing my setup efficiently.
One of the main problems of setting up Emacs is that not only you tend to accumulate so many tricks from EmacsWiki and blog posts that your .emacs has to grow to a full ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs and PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/07/emacs-and-postgresql/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 09:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2010/07/emacs-and-postgresql/</guid>
      <description>Those are my two all times favorite Open Source Software. Or Free Software in the GNU sense of the world, as both the BSD and the GPL are labeled free there. Even if I prefer the The Debian Free Software Guidelines as a global definition and the WTFPL license. But that&amp;rsquo;s a digression.
I think that Emacs and PostgreSQL do share a lot in common. I&amp;rsquo;d begin with the documentation, which quality is amazing for both projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet Another PostgreSQL tool hits debian</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/11/yet-another-postgresql-tool-hits-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 11:49:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/11/yet-another-postgresql-tool-hits-debian/</guid>
      <description>So there it is, this newer contribution of mine that I presented at PGDay is now in debian NEW queue. pg_staging will empower you with respect to what you do about those nightly backups ( pg_dump -Fc or something).
The tool provides a lot of commands to either dump or restore a database. It comes with documentation covering about it all, except for the londiste support part, which will be there in time for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>prefix 1.0.0</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/10/prefix-1.0.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 15:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/10/prefix-1.0.0/</guid>
      <description>So there it is, at long last, the final 1.0.0 release of prefix! It&amp;rsquo;s on its way into the debian repository (targetting sid, in testing in 10 days) and available on pgfoundry to.
In order to make it clear that I intend to maintain this version, the number has 3 digits rather than 2&amp;hellip; which is also what PostgreSQL users will expect.
The only last minute change is that you can now use the first version of the two following rather than the second one:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hstore-new &amp; preprepare reach debian too</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/08/hstore-new--preprepare-reach-debian-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2009 09:14:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/08/hstore-new--preprepare-reach-debian-too/</guid>
      <description>It seems like debian developers are back from annual conference and holiday, so they have had a look at the NEW queue and processed the packages in there. Two of them were mines and waiting to get in unstable, hstore-new and preprepare.
Time to do some bug fixing already, as hstore-new packaging is using a bash&amp;rsquo;ism I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t rely on (or so the debian buildfarm is telling me) and for preprepare I was waiting for inclusion before to go improving the GUC management, stealing some code from Selena&amp;rsquo;s pgGearman :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>prefix 1.0~rc2 in debian testing</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/08/prefix-1.0~rc2-in-debian-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2009 14:50:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/08/prefix-1.0~rc2-in-debian-testing/</guid>
      <description>At long last, here it is. With binary versions both for postgresal-8.3 and postgresal-8.4! Unfortunately my other packaging efforts are still waiting on the NEW queue, but I hope to soon see hstore-new and preprepare enter debian too.
Anyway, the plan for prefix is to now wait something like 2 weeks, then, baring showstopper bugs, release the 1.0 final version. If you have a use for it, now is the good time for testing it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>prefix 1.0~rc2-1</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/07/prefix-1.0~rc2-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 12:48:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/07/prefix-1.0~rc2-1/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been having problem with building both postgresql-8.3-prefix and postgresql-8.4-prefix debian packages from the same source package, and fixing the packaging issue forced me into modifying the main prefix Makefile. So while reaching rc2, I tried to think about missing pieces easy to add this late in the game: and there&amp;rsquo;s one, that&amp;rsquo;s a function length(prefix_range), so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to cast to text no more in the following wildspread query:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>prefix extension reaches 1.0 (rc1)</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/06/prefix-extension-reaches-1.0-rc1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 10:53:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/06/prefix-extension-reaches-1.0-rc1/</guid>
      <description>At long last, after millions and millions of queries just here at work and some more in other places, the prefix project is reaching 1.0 milestone. The release candidate is getting uploaded into debian at the moment of this writing, and available at the following place: prefix-1.0~rc1.tar.gz.
If you have any use for it (as some VoIP companies have already), please consider testing it, in order for me to release a shiny 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>emacs-snapshot</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2008/12/emacs-snapshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2008 16:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2008/12/emacs-snapshot/</guid>
      <description>If you want to live on the bleeding edge, it&amp;rsquo;s easy enough to get a non existing release of GNU Emacs under debian sid, thanks to http://emacs.orebokech.com/.
The problem is that Emacs Muse is broken on emacs-snapshot, partly because of Htmlize which is unable to find the face fonts (I got (error &amp;quot;Invalid face&amp;quot;)), partly because of my configuration itself:
hunk ./dim-muse.el 22 - &#39;((&amp;quot;pgsql.tapoueh.org&amp;quot; $ - (,@(muse-project-alist-dirs &amp;quot;~/dev/muse/site&amp;quot;) $ + &#39;((&amp;quot;pgsql.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>