<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PGQ on The Art of PostgreSQL</title>
    <link>https://tapoueh.org/tags/pgq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PGQ on The Art of PostgreSQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 10:24:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tapoueh.org/tags/pgq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Talking at the SFPUG</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/07/talking-at-the-sfpug/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 10:24:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/07/talking-at-the-sfpug/</guid>
      <description>Those days feel really lucky to me. I&amp;rsquo;m currently visiting friends and customers in San Francisco, and really enjoying my trip here! Of course Josh Berkus took the opportunity to organise a SFPUG meeting and I had the pleasure of being the speaker over there.
My talk was about the most recent version of Skytools and the opportunity to realise that we&amp;rsquo;re still missing a lot on documentation. One of the attendee did propose to help us on that front as he apparently really likes technical writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Upgrading PGQ</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/02/live-upgrading-pgq/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 15:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/02/live-upgrading-pgq/</guid>
      <description>Some skytools related new today, it&amp;rsquo;s been a while. For those who where at my FOSDEM&amp;rsquo;s talk about Implementing High Availability you might have heard that I really like working with PGQ. A new version has been released a while ago, and the most recent verion is now 3.1.3, as announced in the Skytools 3.1.3 email.
Upgrade time!
Skytools 3.1.3 enters debian First news is that Skytools 3.1.3 has been entering debian today (I hope that by the time you reach that URL, it&amp;rsquo;s been updated to show information according to the news here, but I might be early).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean PGQ Subconsumers</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2012/04/clean-pgq-subconsumers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 15:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2012/04/clean-pgq-subconsumers/</guid>
      <description>Now that you&amp;rsquo;re all using the wonders of Cooperative Consumers to help you efficiently and reliably implement your business constraints and offload them from the main user transactions, you&amp;rsquo;re reaching a point where you have to clean up your development environment (because that&amp;rsquo;s what happens to development environments, right?), and you want a way to start again from a clean empty place.
Here we go. It used to be much more simple than that, so if you&amp;rsquo;re still using PGQ from Skytools2, just jump to the next step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PGQ Coop Consumers</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2012/03/pgq-coop-consumers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 14:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2012/03/pgq-coop-consumers/</guid>
      <description>While working a new PostgreSQL architecture for an high scale project that used to be in the top 10 of internet popular web sites (in terms of visitors), I needed to be able to off load some processing from the main path: that&amp;rsquo;s called a batch job. This needs to be transactional: don&amp;rsquo;t run the job if we did rollback; the transaction, process all events that were part of the same transaction in the same transaction, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
