<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Dimitri Fontaine, PostgreSQL Expert</title>
    <link>http://tapoueh.org/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Dimitri Fontaine, PostgreSQL Expert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 01:16:47 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tapoueh.org/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering PostgreSQL in Application Development</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 01:16:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/book/</guid>
      <description>I am writing a book to share my knowledge about how to best use PostgreSQL as an application developer. If you&amp;rsquo;ve evered ask yourself how much should I have my database do for me? this book is for you. If you&amp;rsquo;re thinking that using an ORM might not always be the best option out there, if sometimes you wish SQL was easier to maintain than those concatenated strings with conditionals, then this book can&amp;rsquo;t wait for you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Dimitri Fontaine</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:50:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/about/</guid>
      <description>Dimitri, picture by Oleg Bartunov  Hi! My name is Dimitri. I have been using and contributing to Open Source Software for the best of the last twenty years. I took role as developer, maintainer, packager, release manager, software architect, database architect and administrator, sometimes devops. In the same time frame I also have started several companies (they are still thriving) with a strong Open Source business model, and I have been in manager positions at times too, including at the Executive level in big companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:50:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/projects/</guid>
      <description>Along the years I have been contributing to many projects, and I started some of my own too. If you want to have an idea of the graveyard, have a look at the full repositories page on my GitHub profile: https://github.com/dimitri?tab=repositories. I used to still list some projects like M-x mailq that I&amp;rsquo;ve not been using in a long while, or M-x rcirc-groups-mode that I still use daily, which allows the project to have at least one user&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>