<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emacs Confs on Dimitri Fontaine, PostgreSQL Expert</title>
    <link>http://tapoueh.org/categories/emacs-confs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emacs Confs on Dimitri Fontaine, PostgreSQL Expert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 09:56:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tapoueh.org/categories/emacs-confs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Conference</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/04/emacs-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 09:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/04/emacs-conference/</guid>
      <description>Yes it did happen, for real, in London: the Emacs Conference. It was easter week-end. Yet the conference managed to have more than 60 people meet together and spend a full day talking about Emacs. If you weren&amp;rsquo;t there, a live stream was available and soon enough (wait for about two weeks) the video material will be published, as sacha is working on it.
The conference has been packed with awesome really.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El-Get</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/conf/el-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/conf/el-get/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battle Language à la Marmite</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2012/03/battle-language-%C3%A0-la-marmite/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 14:49:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2012/03/battle-language-%C3%A0-la-marmite/</guid>
      <description>J&amp;rsquo;ai eu la chance hier soir de participer à la Battle Language à la Marmite, où j&amp;rsquo;avais proposé de parler de Emacs Lisp, proposition qui s&amp;rsquo;est transformée en porte-étendard de la grande famille Lisp. J&amp;rsquo;ai utilisé avec plaisir certains contenu de Lisperati dans ma présentation et je vous recommande le détour sur ce site !
   
J&amp;rsquo;ai dans cette présentation très rapide (5 minutes seulement) mentionné l&amp;rsquo;approche axiomatique de John McCarthy lorsqu&amp;rsquo;il a découvert le language, on peut en lire un peu plus sur le site de Paul Graham et son article The Roots of Lisp et le code associé, une implémentation du LISP de McCarthy en common lisp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PGday.eu feedback</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/12/pgday.eu-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 16:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2009/12/pgday.eu-feedback/</guid>
      <description>At pgday there was this form you could fill to give speakers some feedback about their talks. And that&amp;rsquo;s a really nice way as a speaker to know what to improve. And as Magnus was searching a nice looking chart facility in python and I spoke about matplotlib, it felt like having to publish something.
Here is my try at some nice graphics. Well I&amp;rsquo;ll let you decide how nice the result is:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>