<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fosdem on The Art of PostgreSQL</title>
    <link>https://tapoueh.org/tags/fosdem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fosdem on The Art of PostgreSQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 10:36:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tapoueh.org/tags/fosdem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Back From FOSDEM 2015</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2015/02/back-from-fosdem-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 10:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2015/02/back-from-fosdem-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The
&lt;a href=&#34;https://fosdem.org/2015/&#34;&gt;FOSDEM 2015&lt;/a&gt; edition has been awesome this year, the usual mix of meeting
with old friends, talking about interesting topics, seeing tremendous
activity in all Open Source domains, and having Belgium beers in the
evenings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL FOSDEM Conference</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2014/02/postgresql-fosdem-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 10:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2014/02/postgresql-fosdem-conference/</guid>
      <description>Back from the FODESM 2014 Conference, here&amp;rsquo;s the slides I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for the Advanced Extension Use Cases talk I gave, based on the ongoing work to be found under the Tour of Extensions index in this web site.
   
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested into the talk contents, then you might be interested into the following list of articles where I actually did all the work leading to the slides in the above PDF:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSDEM 2014</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2014/01/fosdem-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 11:03:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2014/01/fosdem-2014/</guid>
      <description>This year again the PostgreSQL community is organising a FOSDEM PGDay rigth before the main event. Have a look at the PostgreSQL FOSDEM Schedule, it&amp;rsquo;s packed with awesome talks&amp;hellip; personnaly, it&amp;rsquo;s been awhile since I wanted to see so many of them!
I will be talking about Advanced Extension Use Cases on Friday, see you in Brussels!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Great FOSDEM</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/02/another-great-fosdem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 09:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/02/another-great-fosdem/</guid>
      <description>This year&amp;rsquo;s FOSDEM has been a great edition, in particular the FOSDEM PGDAY 2013 was a great way to begin a 3 days marathon of talking about PostgreSQL with people not only from our community but also from plenty other Open Source communities too: users!
  
  
PostgreSQL at FOSDEM made for a great event
Having had the opportunity to meet more people from those other development communities, I really think we should go and reach for them in their own conferences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sunday at FOSDEM</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/01/a-sunday-at-fosdem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 10:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/01/a-sunday-at-fosdem/</guid>
      <description>The previous article FOSDEM 2013 said to be careful with the PostgreSQL devroom schedule because one of my talks there might get swapped with a slot on the FOSDEM PGDay 2013 which happens this Friday and has been sold out anyway.
Turns out it&amp;rsquo;s not true, because we still depend on past century technologies somehow. Not everybody will be looking at the schedule on the web using a connected mobile device (you know, you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of them, those tracking and surveillance devices, if you want to believe Stallman), and as the schedule gets printed on little paper sheets, it&amp;rsquo;s unfortunately too late to change it now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSDEM 2013</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/01/fosdem-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 10:11:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/01/fosdem-2013/</guid>
      <description>This year again I&amp;rsquo;m going to FOSDEM, and to the extra special PostgreSQL FOSDEM day. It will be the first time that I&amp;rsquo;m going to be at the event for the full week-end rather than just commuting in for the day.
   
I&amp;rsquo;m Going to the FOSDEM, hope to see you there!
And I&amp;rsquo;m presenting two talks over there that are both currently scheduled on the Sunday in the PostgreSQL devroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back from FOSDEM</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/02/back-from-fosdem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 11:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/02/back-from-fosdem/</guid>
      <description>This year we were in the main building of the conference, and apparently the booth went very well, solding lots of PostgreSQL merchandise etc. I had the pleasure to once again meet with the community, but being there only 1 day I didn&amp;rsquo;t spend as much time as I would have liked with some of the people there.
In case you&amp;rsquo;re wondering, my extension&amp;rsquo;s talk went quite well, and several people were kind enough to tell me they appreciated it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to FOSDEM</title>
      <link>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/02/going-to-fosdem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 13:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tapoueh.org/blog/2011/02/going-to-fosdem/</guid>
      <description>A quick blog entry to say that yes:
And I will even do my Extension&amp;rsquo;s talk which had a success at pgday.eu. The talk will be updated to include the last developments of the extension&amp;rsquo;s feature, as some of it changed already in between, and to detail the plan for the ALTER EXTENSION ... UPGRADE feature that I&amp;rsquo;d like to see included as soon as 9.1, but time is running so fast.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>