<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Dimitri Fontaine, PostgreSQL Expert</title>
    <link>http://tapoueh.org/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Dimitri Fontaine, PostgreSQL Expert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 13:30:19 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tapoueh.org/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL and Business Logic</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2017/06/sql-and-business-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 13:30:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2017/06/sql-and-business-logic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Business logic is &lt;em&gt;supposed to be&lt;/em&gt; the part of the application where you
deal with customer or user facing decisions and computations. It is often
argued that this part should be well separated from the rest of the
technical infrastructure of your code. Of course, SQL and relational
database design is meant to support your business cases (or user stories),
so then we can ask ourselves if SQL should be part of your business logic
implementation. Or actually, how much of your business logic should be SQL?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write SQL</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2017/06/how-to-write-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 13:23:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2017/06/how-to-write-sql/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/krisajenkins&#34;&gt;Kris Jenkins&lt;/a&gt; cooked up a very nice way
to embed SQL in your
code: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/krisajenkins/yesql&#34;&gt;YeSQL for Clojure&lt;/a&gt;. The main
idea is that you should be writing your SQL queries in &lt;code&gt;.sql&lt;/code&gt; files in your
code repository and maintain them there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is very good and it is now possible to find alternative
implementations of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://clojure.org&#34;&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;yesql&lt;/em&gt; library in
other languages. Today, we are going to have a look at one of them for
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org&#34;&gt;python&lt;/a&gt; programming
language: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/honza/anosql&#34;&gt;anosql&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with pgloader</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/02/playing-with-pgloader/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 11:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/02/playing-with-pgloader/</guid>
      <description>While making progress with both Event Triggers and Extension Templates, I needed to make a little break. My current keeping sane mental exercise seems to mainly involve using Common Lisp, a programming language that ships with about all the building blocks you need.
Yes, that old language brings so much on the table
When using Common Lisp, you have an awesome interactive development environment where you can redefine function and objects while testing them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pgloader: what&#39;s next?</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/01/pgloader-whats-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 10:48:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/01/pgloader-whats-next/</guid>
      <description>pgloader is a tool to help loading data into PostgreSQL, adding some error management to the COPY command. COPY is the fast way of loading data into PostgreSQL and is transaction safe. That means that if a single error appears within your bulk of data, you will have loaded none of it. pgloader will submit the data again in smaller chunks until it&amp;rsquo;s able to isolate the bad from the good, and then the good is loaded in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost in scope</title>
      <link>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/01/lost-in-scope/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 11:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tapoueh.org/blog/2013/01/lost-in-scope/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Mickael on twitter I got to read an article about loosing scope with some common programming languages. As the blog article Lost in scope references functional programming languages and plays with both Javascript and Erlang, I though I had to try it out with Common Lisp too.
So, here we go with a simple Common Lisp attempt. The Lost in scope article begins with defining a very simple function returning a boolean value, only true when it&amp;rsquo;s not monday.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>